<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_1828_371_T48_6042023116">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">1828.371</ph> Clauses incorporating cross-waivers of liability for International Space Station activities and Science or Space Exploration activities unrelated to the International Space Station.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p outputclass="List1">(a) In contracts covering International Space Station activities, or Science or Space Exploration activities unrelated to the International Space Station that involve a launch, NASA shall require the contractor to agree to waive all claims against any entity or person defined in the clause based on damage arising out of Protected Space Operations. This cross-waiver shall apply only if the person, entity, or property causing the damage is involved in Protected Space Operations and the person, entity, or property damaged is damaged by virtue of its involvement in Protected Space Operations. The cross-waivers will require the contractor to extend the cross-waiver provisions to their subcontractors at any tier and related entities ensuring those subcontractors and related entities also waive all claims against any entity or person defined in the clause for damages arising out of Protected Space Operations. The purpose of the clauses prescribed in this section is to extend the cross-waivers under other agreements to NASA contractors that perform work in support of NASA's obligations under these agreements.
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(b) The contracting officer shall insert the clause at <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_1852_228_78_T48_60423441179"
                  href="Section_1852_228_78_T48_60423441179.dita#Section_1852_228_78_T48_60423441179">1852.228-78</xref>, Cross-Waiver of Liability for Science or Space Exploration Activities unrelated to the International Space Station, in solicitations and contracts above the simplified acquisition threshold for the acquisition of launches for science or space exploration activities unrelated to the International Space Station or for acquisitions for science or space exploration activities that are not related to the International Space Station but involve a launch. If a science or space exploration activity is in support of the International Space Station, the contracting officer shall insert the clause prescribed by paragraph (c) of this section and designate its application to that particular launch.
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(c) The contracting officer shall insert the clause at <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_1852_228_76_T48_60423441178"
                  href="Section_1852_228_76_T48_60423441178.dita#Section_1852_228_76_T48_60423441178">1852.228-76</xref>, Cross-Waiver of Liability for International Space Station Activities, in solicitations and contracts above the simplified acquisition threshold when the work to be performed involves Protected Space Operations, as that term is defined in the clause, relating to the International Space Station.
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(d) At the contracting officer's discretion, the clauses prescribed by paragraphs (b) and (c) of this section may be used in solicitations, contracts, new work modifications, or extensions to existing contracts under the simplified acquisition threshold involving science or space exploration activities unrelated to the International Space Station, or International Space Station activities, respectively, in appropriate circumstances. Examples of such circumstances are when the value of contractor property on a Government installation used in performance of the contract is significant, or when it is likely that the contractor or subcontractor will have its valuable property exposed to risk or damage caused by other participants in the science or space exploration activities unrelated to the International Space Station, or International Space Station activities.
</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
