<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_3452_201_70_T48_7032329111">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">3452.201-70</ph> Contracting Officer's Representative (COR).</title>
      <conbody>
         <p xtrc="P">As prescribed in <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_3401_670_3_T48_703162516"
                  href="Section_3401_670_3_T48_703162516.dita#Section_3401_670_3_T48_703162516">3401.670-3</xref>, insert a clause substantially the same as:
</p>
                                    <p xtrc="HD1">Contracting Officer's Representative (COR) (MAR 2011)
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(a) The Contracting Officer's Representative (COR) is responsible for the technical aspects of the project, technical liaison with the contractor, and any other responsibilities that are specified in the contract. These responsibilities include inspecting all deliverables, including reports, and recommending acceptance or rejection to the contracting officer.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(b) The COR is not authorized to make any commitments or otherwise obligate the Government or authorize any changes that affect the contract price, terms, or conditions. Any contractor requests for changes shall be submitted in writing directly to the contracting officer or through the COR. No such changes shall be made without the written authorization of the contracting officer.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(c) The COR's name and contact information:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(d) The COR may be changed by the Government at any time, but notification of the change, including the name and address of the successor COR, will be provided to the contractor by the contracting officer in writing.</p>
                                 <p xtrc="HD3">(End of clause)


</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
