<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita><concept id="i1032730" outputclass="4">
               <title outputclass="Heading4">5228.301-91 Payment of claims to
third parties.</title>
               <conbody>
                  <p outputclass="Normal">The following procedure shall
be used in making all payments under contracts in which the Government
assumes the risk of liability to third parties and such liability
is not compensated for by insurance or otherwise:</p>
                  <p outputclass="List1">(a) If any suit or action is filed or any
claim is made against the contractor pursuant to the clause at FAR
52.228-7, Insurance--Liability to Third Persons, for loss of or
damage to property, death or bodily injury arising out of performance
of a contract, the contracting officer, in consultation with legal
counsel, shall submit the following information via the HCA to DASN(P) for
a determination as to whether the Government has assumed liability
for the claim and if so, the amount to be paid:</p>
                  <p outputclass="List2">(1) statements of all pertinent facts;</p>
                  <p outputclass="List2">(2) the contracting officer's recommendation
as to the action to be taken with respect to the claim; and</p>
                  <p outputclass="List2">(3) the proposed payment amount.</p>
                  <p outputclass="List1">(b) Unless DASN(P) advises otherwise within
30 calendar days after receipt of the information from the contracting
officer, the third party may be paid the proposed payment amount
unless pursuant to appeal by the contractor under the Disputes clause,
a different amount is allowed.</p>
                  <p outputclass="List1">(c) If DASN(P) determines that the Government
did not assume liability, the contracting officer will be notified
and no payment shall be made, unless pursuant to appeal by the contractor
under the Disputes clause, a different decision is made.</p>
               </conbody>
            </concept></dita>