<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_2452_242_71_T48_60955371146">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">2452.242-71</ph> Contract management system.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p xtrc="P">As prescribed in <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_2442_1107_T48_6095431311"
                  href="Section_2442_1107_T48_6095431311.dita#Section_2442_1107_T48_6095431311">2442.1107</xref>, insert the following clause:
</p>
                                    <p xtrc="HD3">CONTRACT MANAGEMENT SYSTEM (APR 2019)
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(a) The Contractor shall use contract management baseline planning and progress reporting as described herein.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(b) The contract management system shall consist of two parts:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(1) <i>Baseline plan.</i> The baseline plan shall consist of:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List3">(i) A narrative portion that:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List4">(A) Identifies each task and significant activity required for completing the contract work, critical path activities, task dependencies, task milestones, and related deliverables;
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List4">(B) Describes the contract schedule, including the period of time needed to accomplish each task and activity (see paragraph (b)(1)(ii)(B) of this clause);
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List4">(C) Describes staff (e.g., hours per individual), financial, and other resources allocated to each task and significant activity; and
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List4">(D) Provides the rationale for contract work organization and resource allocation.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List3">(ii) A graphic portion showing:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List4">(A) Cumulative planned or budgeted costs of work scheduled for each reporting period over the life of the contract (i.e., the budgeted baseline); and
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List4">(B) The planned start and completion dates of all planned and budgeted tasks and activities.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(2) <i>Progress reports.</i> Progress reports shall consist of:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List3">(i) A narrative portion that:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List4">(A) Provides a brief, concise summary of technical progress made and the costs incurred for each task during the reporting period; and
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List4">(B) Identifies problems, or potential problems that will affect the contract's cost or schedule, the causes of the problems, and the Contractor's proposed corrective actions.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List3">(ii) A graphic portion showing:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List4">(A) The original time-phased, budgeted baseline;
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List4">(B) The schedule status and degree of completion of the tasks, activities, and deliverables shown in the baseline plan for the reporting period, including actual start and completion dates for all tasks and activities in the baseline plan; and
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List4">(C) The costs incurred during the reporting period, the current total amount of costs incurred through the end date of the reporting period for budgeted work, and the projected costs required to complete the work under the contract.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(3) <i>Reporting frequency.</i> The reports described in paragraph (b)(2) of this clause shall be submitted [insert period, <i>e.g.,</i> monthly, quarterly, or schedule based on when payments will be made under the contract].
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(c) The formats, forms, and/or software to be used for the contract management system under this contract shall be [Contracting Officer insert appropriate language, such as “as prescribed in the schedule;” “a format, forms and/or software designated by the COR” or, “the Contractor's own format, forms and/or software, subject to the approval of the COR.”].
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(d) When this clause applies to individual task orders under the contract, the word “contract” shall mean “task order.”</p>
                                 <p xtrc="HD3">(End of clause)


</p>
         <p xtrc="P">
                                    <i>Alternate I</i> (FEB 2006). As prescribed in <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_2442_1107_T48_6095431311"
                  href="Section_2442_1107_T48_6095431311.dita#Section_2442_1107_T48_6095431311">2442.1107</xref>, replace paragraph (b) with the following:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(b) The contract management system shall consist of two parts:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(1) <i>Baseline plan.</i> The baseline plan shall consist of:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List3">(i) A narrative portion that:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List4">(A) Identifies each task and significant activity required for completing the contract work, critical path activities, task dependencies, task milestones, and related deliverables;
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List4">(B) Describes the contract work schedule, including the period of time needed to accomplish each task and activity (see paragraph (ii) of this section below);
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List4">(C) Describes key personnel allocated to each task and significant activity; and,
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List4">(D) Provides the rationale for contract work organization.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List3">(ii) A graphic portion showing the planned start and completion dates of all planned tasks and activities.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(2) <i>Progress reports.</i> Progress reports shall consist of:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List3">(i) A narrative portion that:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List4">(A) Provides a brief, concise summary of technical progress made for each task during the reporting period; and
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List4">(B) Identifies problems, or potential problems, that will affect the contract's cost or schedule, their causes, and the contractor's proposed corrective actions.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List3">(ii) A graphic portion showing the schedule status and degree of completion of the tasks, activities, and deliverables shown in the baseline plan for the reporting period, including actual start and completion dates for all tasks and activities in the baseline plan.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(3) <i>Reporting frequency.</i> The reports described in (b)(2) shall be submitted [<i>insert period, e.g., monthly, quarterly, or schedule</i>].</p>
                                 <p xtrc="HD3">(End of clause)
</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
