<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_2452_237_82_T48_60955371142">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">2452.237-82</ph> Access to controlled unclassified information (CUI).</title>
      <conbody>
         <p xtrc="P">As prescribed in HUDAR <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_2437_110_T48_6095330111"
                  href="Section_2437_110_T48_6095330111.dita#Section_2437_110_T48_6095330111">2437.110</xref>(e)(7), the Contracting Officer shall insert provision <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_2452_237_82_T48_60955371142"
                  href="Section_2452_237_82_T48_60955371142.dita#Section_2452_237_82_T48_60955371142">2452.237-82</xref> in Section L of solicitations when controlled unclassified information (CUI), as defined in the provision, will be provided to potential offerors for the purpose of preparing offers.
</p>
                                    <p xtrc="HD3">ACCESS TO CONTROLLED UNCLASSIFIED INFORMATION (CUI) (APR 2019)
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(a) For the sole purpose of preparing an offer in response to this solicitation, HUD may make certain controlled unclassified information (CUI) available to prospective offerors.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(b) CUI:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(1) Is any information which the loss, misuse, or modification of, or unauthorized access to, could adversely affect the national interest or the conduct of Federal programs or the privacy to which individuals are entitled under section 552a of title 5, United States Code (the Privacy Act), but which has not been specifically authorized under criteria established by an Executive Order or an Act of Congress to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or foreign policy;
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(2) Is not available to the general public;
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(3) May include:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List3">(i) Government acquisition-sensitive information, including source selection information as defined at section 2.101 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation (48 CFR chapter 1); contractor bid or proposal information;
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List3">(ii) Information contained in individual contracts that is not public information and such contract information that is contained in Government databases; proprietary economic, financial, or business information (<i>e.g.,</i> salary information) provided to the Government by other parties (<i>e.g.,</i> other contractors) or belonging to HUD;
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List3">(iii) Personally identifiable information (PII) that includes, but is not limited to, Social Security numbers, names, dates of birth, places of birth, parents' names, credit card numbers, applications for entitlements, and information relating to a person's private financial, income, employment, and tax records; and
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List3">(iv) Other information that the HUD Contracting Officer (CO) or other authorized HUD employee explicitly identifies as CUI.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(4) May exist in various physical media (<i>e.g.,</i> paper, electronic file, audio, or video disc), may be transmitted orally, developed under or pre-exist any related contract, and may be in its original form, or a derivative form (<i>i.e.,</i> where the information has been included in contractor-generated work, or where it is discernible from materials incorporating or based upon such information).
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(c) As a prior condition to being provided access to any CUI, each prospective offeror shall execute the following nondisclosure agreements and deliver the executed agreements to the Contracting Officer:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(1) Nondisclosure Agreement between the Department of Housing and Urban Development (“HUD”) and Offeror Granting Conditional Access to Controlled Unclassified Information (“Offeror Agreement”) (see Attachment J-__[<i>contracting officer insert attachment number</i>]). This agreement must be executed by an officer or other representative of the company authorized to bind the firm to the commitments made by the agreement and the individual nondisclosure agreements executed by those offeror employees or representatives to whom the sensitive information will be provided.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(2) Nondisclosure Agreement between the Department of Housing and Urban Development and Offeror Employee or Other External Party Granting Conditional Access to Controlled Unclassified Information (“Nondisclosure Agreement”) (see Attachment J-_ [<i>contracting officer insert attachment number</i>]). A separate agreement must be executed by each person to whom access to CUI will be provided, regardless of whether HUD or the Offeror provides such access. The offeror is responsible for ensuring that each individual who is provided access to CUI executes a nondisclosure agreement.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(3) Nondisclosure agreements must be submitted to the CO and COR within ten (10) days after contract award or as otherwise specified by the CO.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(d) CUI will be provided to prospective offerors as follows: [<i>describe how information will be provided including: The party responsible for providing access to information, the procedure for obtaining access, and the format in which the information is contained; e.g., “by the contracting officer on compact disk (CD) at the pre-proposal meeting</i>].
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(e) The offeror's failure to comply with any part of this provision or with the terms of the required nondisclosure agreements may disqualify the offeror for consideration of any contract awarded under this solicitation.</p>
                                 <p xtrc="HD3">(End of Provision)
</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
