<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_3424_170_T48_7031917112">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">3424.170</ph> Protection of human subjects.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p xtrc="P">In this subsection, “Research” means a systematic investigation, including research development, testing and evaluation, designed to develop or contribute to generalizable knowledge. (34 CFR 97.102(d)) Research is considered to involve human subjects when a researcher obtains information about a living individual through intervention or interaction with the individual or obtains personally identifiable private information about an individual. Some categories of research are exempt under the regulations, and the exemptions are in 34 CFR part 97.
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(a) The contracting officer must insert the provision in <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_3452_224_71_T48_70323291111"
                  href="Section_3452_224_71_T48_70323291111.dita#Section_3452_224_71_T48_70323291111">3452.224-71</xref> (Notice about research activities involving human subjects) in any solicitation where a resultant contract will include, or is likely to include, research activities involving human subjects covered under 34 CFR part 97.
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(b) The contracting officer must insert the clause at <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_3452_224_72_T48_70323291112"
                  href="Section_3452_224_72_T48_70323291112.dita#Section_3452_224_72_T48_70323291112">3452.224-72</xref> (Research activities involving human subjects) in any solicitation that includes the provision in <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_3452_224_71_T48_70323291111"
                  href="Section_3452_224_71_T48_70323291111.dita#Section_3452_224_71_T48_70323291111">3452.224-71</xref> (Notice about research activities involving human subjects) and in any resultant contract.


</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
