<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_1252_219_71_T48_50542332118">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">1252.219-71</ph> Section 8(a) Direct Awards.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p xtrc="P">As prescribed in (TAR) 48 CFR 1219.811-3(f), insert the following clause:
</p>
                                    <p xtrc="HD1">Section 8(A) Direct Awards (APR 2005)
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(a) This contract is issued as a direct award between the contracting activity and the 8(a) contractor pursuant to the Partnership Agreement between the Small Business Administration (SBA) and the Department of Transportation. SBA does retain responsibility for 8(a) certification, 8(a) eligibility determinations and related issues, and providing counseling and assistance to the 8(a) contractor under the 8(a) program. The responsible SBA district office is: [To be completed by Contracting Officer at time of award]
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(b) The contracting activity is responsible for administering the contract and taking any action on behalf of the Government under the terms and conditions of the contract. However, the contracting activity shall give advance notice to the SBA before it issues a final notice terminating performance, either in whole or in part, under the contract. The contracting activity shall also coordinate with SBA prior to processing any novation agreement. The contracting activity may assign contract administration functions to a contract administration office.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(c) The contractor agrees:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(1) To notify the Contracting Officer, simultaneous with its notification to SBA (as required by SBA's 8 (a) regulations), when the owner or owners upon whom 8(a) eligibility is based plan to relinquish ownership or control of the concern. Consistent with 15 U.S.C. 637(a)(21), transfer of ownership or control shall result in termination of the contract for convenience, unless SBA waives the requirement for termination prior to the actual relinquishing of ownership and control.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(2) To adhere to the requirements of 52.219-14, Limitations on Subcontracting.</p>
                                 <p xtrc="HD3">(End of clause) 


</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
