<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_2804_902_T48_6011605512">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">2804.902</ph> Contract information.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p outputclass="List1">(a) Pursuant to FAR 4.902, the HCA, or delegate, shall certify to the PE, in the format specified in this section, under penalty of perjury, that such official has examined the information submitted by that bureau as its FPDS data, that the data has been prepared pursuant to the requirement of 26 U.S.C. 6050M, and that, to the best of such official's knowledge and belief it is compiled from bureau records maintained in the normal course of business for the purpose of making a true, correct and complete return as required by 26 U.S.C. 6050M.
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(b) The following certification will be signed and dated by the HCA, or delegate, and submitted with each bureau quarterly FPDS report (as specified by <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_2804_602_T48_6011605311"
                  href="Section_2804_602_T48_6011605311.dita#Section_2804_602_T48_6011605311">2804.602</xref>).</p>
                                    <p xtrc="HD3">CERTIFICATION
</p>
                                    <p xtrc="P">I, ____________(Name),
</p>
                                    <p xtrc="FP">______________ (Title) under the penalties of perjury have examined the information to be submitted by ____________ (Bureau) to the Procurement Executive, for making information returns on behalf of the Department of Justice to the Internal Revenue Service, and certify that this information has been prepared pursuant to the requirements of 26 U.S.C. 6050M and that it is to the best of my knowledge and belief, a compilation of bureau records maintained in the normal course of business for the purpose of providing true, correct and complete returns as required by 26 U.S.C. 6050M.
</p>
                                    <p xtrc="FP-DASH">Signature
</p>
                                    <p xtrc="FP-DASH">Date</p>
                                 <p outputclass="List1">(c) The PE will certify the consolidated FPDS data for the Department, transmit the data to the Federal Procurement Data Center (FPDC) and authorize the FPDC to make returns to the IRS on behalf of the agency.


</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
