<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_2801_601_T48_6011602511">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">2801.601</ph> General.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p outputclass="List1">(a) In accordance with Attorney General Order 1687-93, the authority vested in the Attorney General with respect to contractual actions, for goods and services, is delegated to the following officials:
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(1) AAG/A (for the offices, boards, and divisions (OBDs);
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(2) Director, Federal Bureau of Investigation;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(3) Director, Federal Bureau of Prisons;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(4) Commissioner, Federal Prison Industries;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(5) Commissioner, Immigration and Naturalization Service;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(6) Administrator, Drug Enforcement Administration;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(7) Assistant Attorney General, Office of Justice Programs;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(8) Director, U.S. Marshals Service;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(9) Inspector General, Office of the Inspector General.
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(b) The acquisition authority delegated to the officials in <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_2801_601_T48_6011602511"
                  href="Section_2801_601_T48_6011602511.dita#Section_2801_601_T48_6011602511">2801.601</xref>(a) may be redelegated to subordinate officials as necessary for the efficient and proper administration of the Department's acquisition operations. Such redelegated authority shall expressly state whether it carries the power of redelegation of authority.
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(c) The redelegation of contracting authority directly to specific persons without regard for intermediate organizational levels only establishes authority to represent the Government in its commercial business dealings. It is not intended to affect the organizational relationship between the contracting officers and higher administrative and supervisory levels in the performance of their duties.


</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
