<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_1852_227_19_T48_60423441167">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">1852.227-19</ph> Commercial computer software - Restricted rights (JUL 1997).</title>
      <conbody>
         <p outputclass="List1">(a) As prescribed in <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_1827_409_T48_6042022213"
                  href="Section_1827_409_T48_6042022213.dita#Section_1827_409_T48_6042022213">1827.409</xref>(k)(i), add the following paragraph (e) to the basic clause at FAR 52.227-19:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(e) For the purposes of receiving updates, correction notices, consultation information, or other similar information regarding any computer software delivered under this contract/purchase order, the NASA Contracting Officer or the NASA Contracting Officer's Technical Representative/User may sign any vendor supplied agreements, registration forms, or cards and return them directly to the vendor; however, such signing shall not alter any of the rights or obligations of either NASA or the vendor set forth in this clause or elsewhere in this contract/purchase order.</p>
                                 <p xtrc="HD3">(End of addition)
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(b) As prescribed in <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_1827_409_T48_6042022213"
                  href="Section_1827_409_T48_6042022213.dita#Section_1827_409_T48_6042022213">1827.409</xref>(k)(ii), add the following paragraph (f) to the basic clause at FAR 52.227-19:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(f) Subject to paragraphs (a) through (e) above, those applicable portions of the Contractor's standard commercial license or lease agreement pertaining to any computer software delivered under this purchase order/contract that are consistent with Federal laws, standard industry practices, and the Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR) shall be incorporated into and made part of this purchase order/contract.</p>
                                 <p xtrc="HD3">(End of addition)
</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
