<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_2952_201_70_T48_701740111">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">2952.201-70</ph> Contracting Officer's Technical Representative (COTR).</title>
      <conbody>
         <p xtrc="P">Insert the following clause into contracts requiring COTR representation under <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_2901_603_T48_70112615"
                  href="Section_2901_603_T48_70112615.dita#Section_2901_603_T48_70112615">2901.603</xref>.71: 
</p>
                                    <p xtrc="P">
                                       <i>Contracting officer's technical representative (COTR)</i> May 2004 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(a) Mr./Ms. (Name) of (Organization) (Room No.), (Building), (Address), (Area Code &amp; Telephone No.), is hereby designated to act as contracting officer's technical representative (COTR) under this contract.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(b) The COTR is responsible, as applicable, for: receiving all deliverables; inspecting and accepting the supplies or services provided hereunder in accordance with the terms and conditions of this contract; providing direction to the contractor which clarifies the contract effort, fills in details or otherwise serves to accomplish the contractual scope of work; evaluating performance; and certifying all invoices/vouchers for acceptance of the supplies or services furnished for payment.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(c) The COTR does not have the authority to alter the contractor's obligations under the contract, and/or modify any of the expressed terms, conditions, specifications, or cost of the agreement. If, as a result of technical discussions, it is desirable to alter/change contractual obligations or the scope of work, the contracting officer must issue such changes.</p>
                                 </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
