<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="d1e2178" outputclass="Section">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">3009.171-5</ph> Serious felonies prohibiting award.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p outputclass="List1">(a) Only serious felony convictions will prohibit a business concern from being awarded a contract for FPS guard services. Serious felonies that will prohibit contract award are any felonies that involve dishonesty, fraud, deceit, misrepresentation, or deliberate violence; that reflect adversely on the individual's honesty, trustworthiness, or fitness to own, control, or operate a business concern; that cast doubt on the integrity or business ethics of the business concern; or are of a nature that is inconsistent with the mission of FPS, including, without limitation, those felonies listed in paragraphs (b)(1) through (12) of this subsection.
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(b) The following is a list of offenses determined by DHS to be serious felonies for purposes of the Federal Protective Service Guard Reform Act of 2008. Except as provided in (HSAR) 48 CFR 3009.171-7(f), award of a contract for FPS guard services will not be made to any business that is owned, controlled, or operated by an individual who has been convicted of a felony involving:
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(1) Fraud of any type, including those arising out of a procurement contract, cooperative agreement, grant or other assistance relationship with the federal, state or local government, as well as, without limitation, embezzlement, fraudulent conversion, false claims or statements, kickbacks, misappropriations of property, unfair or deceptive trade practices, or restraint of trade;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(2) Bribery, graft, or a conflict of interest;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(3) Threatened or actual harm to a government official or family member;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(4) Threatened or actual harm to government property;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(5) A crime of violence;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(6) A threat to national security;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(7) Commercial bribery, counterfeiting, or forgery;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(8) Obstruction of justice, perjury or subornation of perjury, or bribery of a witness;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(9) An attempt to evade or defeat Federal tax;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(10) Willful failure to collect or pay over Federal tax;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(11) Trafficking in illegal drugs, alcohol, firearms, explosives, or other weapons;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(12) Immigration violations (e.g., 8 U.S.C. 1324, 1324c, 1326); and
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(13) Any other felony that involves dishonesty, fraud, deceit, misrepresentation, or deliberate violence; that reflects adversely on the individual's honesty, trustworthiness, or fitness to own, control, or operate a business concern; that casts doubt on the integrity or business ethics of the business concern; or is of a nature that is inconsistent with the mission of FPS.
</p>
         <p outputclass="CITA">[74 FR 58856, Nov. 16, 2009]


</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
