<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="d1e7741" outputclass="Section">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">3052.247-70</ph> F.o.b. origin information.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p outputclass="P">As prescribed in (HSAR) 48 CFR 3047.305-70(a), insert the following provision:
</p>
         <note>
                                 <p outputclass="HD1">F.O.B. Origin Information (DEC 2003)
</p>
                                 <p outputclass="P">The offeror shall furnish information with the offer:
</p>
                                 <p outputclass="List1">(a) Location of the offeror's actual shipping point(s) (street address, city, state, and zip code) from which supplies will be delivered to the Government;
</p>
                                 <p outputclass="List1">(b) Whether the offered shipping point has a private railroad siding, and the name of the rail carrier serving it;
</p>
                                 <p outputclass="List1">(c) When the offered shipping point does not have a private siding, the names and addresses of the nearest public rail siding and of the carrier serving it; and
</p>
                                 <p outputclass="List1">(d) The quantity of supplies to be shipped from each shipping point.</p>
                              </note>
         <p outputclass="HD3">(End of provision)
</p>
         <p outputclass="P">
                                 <i>Alternate I</i> (DEC 2003). If delivery is “f.o.b. origin, contractor's facility,” and the designated facility is not covered by the line-haul transportation rate, add the following paragraph to the basic provision:
</p>
         <note>
                                 <p outputclass="List1">(e) The charges required to deliver the shipment to the point where the line-haul rate is applicable.</p>
                              </note>
         <p outputclass="P">
                                 <i>Alternate II</i> (DEC 2003). When delivery is “f.o.b. origin, freight allowed,” add the following paragraph to the basic provision:
</p>
         <note>
                                 <p outputclass="List1">(e) The basis on which transportation charges will be allowed, including the origin and destination from and to which transportation charges will be allowed.</p>
                              </note>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
