<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_2052_209_70_T48_6063825114">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">2052.209-70</ph> Current/former agency employee involvement.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p xtrc="P">As prescribed at <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_2009_105_70_T48_606327112"
                  href="Section_2009_105_70_T48_606327112.dita#Section_2009_105_70_T48_606327112">2009.105-70</xref>, the contracting officer shall insert the following provision in all solicitations:
</p>
                                    <p xtrc="HD1">Current/Former Agency Employee Involvement (OCT 1999)
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(a) The following representation is required by the NRC Acquisition Regulation <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_2009_105_70_T48_606327112"
                  href="Section_2009_105_70_T48_606327112.dita#Section_2009_105_70_T48_606327112">2009.105-70</xref>(b). It is not NRC policy to encourage offerors and contractors to propose current/former agency employees to perform work under NRC contracts and as set forth in the above cited provision, the use of such employees may, under certain conditions, adversely affect NRC's consideration of non-competitive proposals and task orders.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(b) There ( ) are ( ) are no current/former NRC employees (including special Government employees performing services as experts, advisors, consultants, or members of advisory committees) who have been or will be involved, directly or indirectly, in developing the offer, or in negotiating on behalf of the offeror, or in managing, administering, or performing any contract, consultant agreement, or subcontract resulting from this offer. For each individual so identified, the Technical and Management proposal must contain, as a separate attachment, the name of the individual, the individual's title while employed by the NRC, the date individual left NRC, and a brief description of the individual's role under this proposal.</p>
                                 <p xtrc="HD3">(End of provision)


</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
