<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_1852_219_77_T48_60423441146">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">1852.219-77</ph> NASA Mentor-Protégé Program.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p xtrc="P">As prescribed in <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_1819_7215_T48_6041917519"
                  href="Section_1819_7215_T48_6041917519.dita#Section_1819_7215_T48_6041917519">1819.7215</xref>, insert the following clause:
</p>
                                    <p xtrc="HD1">NASA Mentor-Protégé Program (APR 2015)
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(a) Prime contractors are encouraged to participate in the NASA Mentor-Protégé Program for the purpose of providing developmental assistance to eligible protégé entities to enhance their capabilities and increase their participation in NASA contracts.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(b) The Program consists of:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(1) Mentors, which are large businesses and prime contractors with at least one active and approved NASA subcontracting plan;
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(2) Protégés, which are subcontractors to the prime contractor. Protégés must qualify as small disadvantaged business concerns, women-owned small business concerns, veteran-owned or service-disabled veteran-owned small business concerns, HUBZone small business concerns, Historically Black Colleges and Universities, minority institutions of higher education, meeting the qualifications defined in FAR part 2, Definitions of Parts and Term, active NASA SBIR Phase II companies or nonprofit agencies employing people who are blind or severely disabled as defined in 41 CFR Chapter 51.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(3) Mentor-protégé agreements endorsed by the cognizant NASA centers and approved by the NASA Office of Small Business Programs (OSBP);
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(4) In contracts with award fee incentives, potential for payment of an award fee for voluntary participation and successful performance in the Mentor-Protégé Program, in accordance with NFS 1819.7208.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(c) Mentor participation in the Program, described in NFS <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Subpart_1819_72_T48_60419175"
                  href="Subpart_1819_72_T48_60419175.dita#Subpart_1819_72_T48_60419175">1819.72</xref>, means providing technical, managerial and financial assistance to aid protégés in developing requisite high-tech expertise and business systems to compete for and successfully perform NASA contracts and subcontracts.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(d) Contractors interested in participating in the program are encouraged to contact the NASA OSBP, Washington, DC 20546, (202) 358-2088, for further information.</p>
                                 <p xtrc="HD3">(End of clause) 
</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
