<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_352_270_13_T48_4018362146">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">352.270-13</ph> Continued Ban on Funding Abortion and Continued Ban on Funding of Human Embryo Research.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p xtrc="P">As prescribed in HHSAR 370.304(e), the Contracting Officer shall insert the following clause:
</p>
                                    <p xtrc="HD1">Continued Ban on Funding Abortion and Continued Ban on Funding of Human Embryo Research (DEC 2015)
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(a) The Contractor shall not use any funds obligated under this contract for any abortion.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(b) The Contractor shall not use any funds obligated under this contract for the following:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(1) The creation of a human embryo or embryos for research purposes; or
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(2) Research in which a human embryo or embryos are destroyed, discarded, or knowingly subjected to risk of injury of death greater than that allowed for research on fetuses in utero under 45 CFR part 46 and Section 498(b) of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. 289g(b)).
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(c) The term “human embryo or embryos” includes any organism, not protected as a human subject under 45 CFR part 46 as of the date of the enactment of this Act, that is derived by fertilization, parthenogenesis, cloning, or any other means from one or more human gametes of human diploid cells.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(d) The Contractor shall not use any Federal funds for the cloning of human beings.</p>
                                 <p xtrc="HD3">(End of clause)


</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
