<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_315_605_T48_401316411">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">315.605</ph> Content of unsolicited proposals.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p outputclass="List1">(d) <i>Warranty by offeror.</i> To ensure against contacts between HHS personnel and prospective offerors that would exceed the limits of advance guidance set forth in FAR 15.604 and potentially result in an unfair advantage to an offeror, the prospective offeror of an unsolicited proposal must include the following warranty in any unsolicited proposal. Contracting officers receiving an unsolicited proposal without this warranty shall not process the proposal until the offeror is notified of the missing language and given an opportunity to submit a proper warranty. If no warranty is provided in a reasonable time, the contracting officer shall reject the unsolicited proposal, notify the offeror of the rejection, and document the actions in the file.
</p>
         <p xtrc="HD1">UNSOLICITED PROPOSAL
</p>
         <p xtrc="HD1">WARRANTY BY OFFEROR
</p>
         <p xtrc="P">This is to warrant that - 
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(a) This proposal has not been prepared under Government supervision;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(b) The methods and approaches stated in the proposal were developed by this offeror;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(c) Any contact with HHS personnel has been within the limits of appropriate advance guidance set forth in FAR 15.604; and,
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(d) No prior commitments were received from HHS personnel regarding acceptance of this proposal.
</p>
                                    <p xtrc="FP-DASH">Date:
</p>
                                    <p xtrc="FP-DASH">Organization:
</p>
                                    <p xtrc="FP-DASH">Name:
</p>
                                    <p xtrc="FP-DASH">Title:</p>
                                 <p xtrc="P">(This warranty shall be signed by a responsible management official of the proposing organization who is a person authorized to contractually obligate the organization.)


</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
