<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_852_236_71_T48_50216422147">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">852.236-71</ph> Specifications and Drawings for Construction.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p xtrc="P">As prescribed in 836.521, insert the following clause:
</p>
                                    <p xtrc="HD1">Specifications and Drawings for Construction (APR 2019)
</p>
                                    <p xtrc="P">The clause entitled “Specifications and Drawings for Construction” in FAR

52.236-21 is supplemented as follows:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(a) The Contracting Officer's interpretation of the drawings and specifications will be final, subject to the Disputes clause.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(b) The Contractor shall - 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(1) Check all drawings and specifications furnished immediately upon receipt;
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(2) Compare all drawings and the specifications, and verify the figures before laying out the work;
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(3) Promptly notify the Contracting Officer of any discrepancies;
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(4) Be responsible for any errors that might have been avoided by complying with this paragraph (b); and
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(5) Reproduce and print contract drawings and specifications as needed.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(c) In general - 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(1) Drawings of greater detail shall govern over drawings of lesser detail unless specifically noted otherwise; and
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(2) Figures and numerical quantities noted on drawings govern over scale measurements.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(d) Omissions from the drawings or specifications or the misdescription of details of work that are manifestly necessary to carry out the intent of the drawings and specifications, or that are customarily performed, shall not relieve the Contractor from performing such omitted or misdescribed details of the work. The Contractor shall perform such details as if fully and correctly set forth and described in the drawings and specifications.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(e) The work shall conform to the specifications and the contract drawings identified on the following index of drawings:
</p>
                                    <p xtrc="FP">Title  File  Drawing No.</p>
                                 <p xtrc="HD3">(End of clause)
</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
