<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_852_219_9_T48_50216422128">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">852.219-9</ph> VA Small Business Subcontracting Plan Minimum Requirements.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p xtrc="P">As prescribed in subpart 819.709, insert the following clause:
</p>
                                 <p xtrc="HD1">VA Small Business Subcontracting Plan Minimum Requirements (DEC 2009)
</p>
                                 <p outputclass="List1">(a) This clause does not apply to small business concerns.
</p>
                                 <p outputclass="List1">(b) If the offeror is required to submit an individual subcontracting plan, the minimum goals for award of subcontracts to service-disabled veteran-owned small business concerns and veteran-owned small business concerns shall be at least commensurate with the Department's annual service-disabled veteran-owned small business and veteran-owned small business prime contracting goals for the total dollars planned to be subcontracted.
</p>
                                 <p outputclass="List1">(c) For a commercial plan, the minimum goals for award of subcontracts to service-disabled veteran-owned small business concerns and veteran-owned small businesses shall be at least commensurate with the Department's annual service-disabled veteran-owned small business and veteran-owned small business prime contracting goals for the total value of projected subcontracts to support the sales for the commercial plan.
</p>
                                 <p outputclass="List1">(d) To be credited toward goal achievements, businesses must be verified as eligible in the Vendor Information Pages database. The contractor shall annually submit a listing of service-disabled veteran-owned small businesses and veteran-owned small businesses for which credit toward goal achievement is to be applied for the review of personnel in the Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization.
</p>
                                 <p outputclass="List1">(e) The contractor may appeal any businesses determined not eligible for crediting toward goal achievements by following the procedures contained in 819.407. </p>
                              <p xtrc="HD3">(End of clause) 
</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
