<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_832_202_4_T48_5021329213">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">832.202-4</ph> Security for Government financing.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p props="Runin" outputclass="List1">(a)(2) An offeror's financial condition may be considered adequate security to protect the Government's interest when the Government provides contract financing. In assessing the offeror's financial condition, the contracting officer may obtain, to the extent required, the following information - 
</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(i) A current year interim balance sheet and income statement and balance sheets and income statements for the two preceding fiscal years. The statements should be prepared in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles and must be audited and certified by an independent public accountant or an appropriate officer of the firm;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(ii) A cash flow forecast for the remainder of the contract term showing the planned origin and use of cash within the firm or branch performing the contract;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(iii) Information on financing arrangements disclosing the availability of cash to finance contract performance, the contractor's exposure to financial risk, and credit arrangements;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(iv) A statement of the status of all State, local, and Federal tax accounts, including any special mandatory contributions;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(v) A description and explanation of the financial effects of any leases, deferred purchase arrangements, patent or royalty arrangements, insurance, planned capital expenditures, pending claims, contingent liabilities, and other financial aspects of the business; and
</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(vi) Any other financial information deemed necessary.
</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
