<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_2452_237_83_T48_60955371143">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">2452.237-83</ph> Access to controlled unclassified information (CUI).</title>
      <conbody>
         <p xtrc="P">As prescribed in HUDAR <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_2437_110_T48_6095330111"
                  href="Section_2437_110_T48_6095330111.dita#Section_2437_110_T48_6095330111">2437.110</xref>(e)(8), the Contracting Officer shall insert clause <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_2452_237_83_T48_60955371143"
                  href="Section_2452_237_83_T48_60955371143.dita#Section_2452_237_83_T48_60955371143">2452.237-83</xref> in Section H of solicitations and contracts under which contractor and/or subcontractor employees will be granted access to controlled unclassified information as defined in the clause.
</p>
                                    <p xtrc="HD3">ACCESS TO CONTROLLED UNCLASSIFIED INFORMATION (CUI) (APR 2019)
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(a) For the sole purpose of performing work required under this contract, the contracting officer may grant the contractor - including contractor employees, subcontractors, and subcontractor employees - access to controlled unclassified information (CUI).
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(b) CUI:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(1) Is any information which the loss, misuse, or modification of, or unauthorized access to, could adversely affect the national interest or the conduct of Federal programs or the privacy to which individuals are entitled under section 552a of title 5, United States Code (the Privacy Act), but which has not been specifically authorized under criteria established by an Executive Order or an Act of Congress to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or foreign policy;
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(2) Is not available to the general public;
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(3) May include:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List3">(i) Government acquisition-sensitive information, including source selection information as defined at section 2.101 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation (48 CFR chapter 1); contractor bid or proposal information;
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List3">(ii) Information contained in individual contracts that is not public information and such contract information that is contained in Government databases; proprietary economic, financial, or business information (<i>e.g.,</i> salary information) provided to the Government by other parties (<i>e.g.,</i> other contractors) or belonging to HUD;
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List3">(iii) Personally identifiable information (PII) that includes, but is not limited to social security numbers, names, dates of birth, places of birth, parents' names, credit card numbers, applications for entitlements, and information relating to a person's private financial, income, employment, and tax records; and
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List3">(iv) Other information that the HUD contracting officer or other authorized HUD employee explicitly identifies as CUI; and
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(4) May exist in various physical media (<i>e.g.,</i> paper, electronic file, audio or video disc) or be transmitted orally, may be developed under or pre-exist any related contract, and may be in its original form or a derivative form (<i>i.e.,</i> where the information has been included in contractor-generated work, or where it is discernible from materials incorporating or based upon such information).
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(c) As a prior condition to being provided access to any CUI, each contractor or subcontractor employee shall execute the nondisclosure agreement in attachment J._ [<i>contracting officer insert attachment number</i>] to this contract and deliver the executed agreement to the contracting officer.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(d) The Contractor shall include this clause in all subcontracts.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(e) The contractor's failure to comply with any part of this clause or with the terms of the required nondisclosure agreements may result in the termination of this contract for default.</p>
                                 <p xtrc="HD3">(End of Clause)
</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
