<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_904_7101_T48_503185612">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">904.7101</ph> Definitions.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p xtrc="P">
                                    <i>Effectively owned or controlled</i> means that a foreign government or an entity controlled by a foreign government has the power, either directly or indirectly, whether exercised or exercisable, to control or influence the election or appointment of the Offeror's officers, directors, partners, regents, trustees, or a majority of the Offeror's board of directors by any means, e.g., ownership, contract, or operation of law.
</p>
         <p xtrc="P">
                                    <i>Entity controlled by a foreign government</i> means any domestic or foreign organization or corporation that is effectively owned or controlled by a foreign government or any individual acting on behalf of a foreign government. See subpart 925.7 for a statement of the prohibition on certain foreign purchases.
</p>
         <p xtrc="P">
                                    <i>Foreign government</i> means any governing body organized and existing under the laws of any country other than the United States and its possessions and trust territories and any agent or instrumentality of that government.
</p>
         <p xtrc="P">
                                    <i>Proscribed information</i> means - 
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">
				</p><p outputclass="List2">(1) 
			Top Secret information;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(2) Communications Security (COMSEC) information, except classified keys used to operate secure telephone units (STU IIIs);
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(3) Restricted Data, as defined in the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, as amended;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(4) Special Access Program (SAP) information; or
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(5) Sensitive Compartmented Information (SCI).
</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
