<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_925_7001_T48_5032122612">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">925.7001</ph> Definitions.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p xtrc="P">
                                    <i>Costs related to the decommissioning of nuclear facilities,</i> as used in this subpart, means any cost associated with the compliance with regulatory requirements governing the decommissioning of nuclear facilities licensed by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission. Such costs for foreign facilities and for Department of Energy facilities are costs of decommissioning associated with the compliance with foreign regulatory requirements or the Department's own requirements.
</p>
         <p xtrc="P">
                                    <i>Costs related to the storage and disposal of nuclear waste,</i> as used in this subpart, means any costs, whether required by regulation or incurred as a matter of prudent business practice, associated with the storage or disposal of nuclear waste.
</p>
         <p xtrc="P">
                                    <i>Foreign company,</i> as used in this subpart, means a company which offers to perform nuclear hot cell services at a facility which is not subject to the laws and regulations of the United States, its agencies, and its political subdivisions.
</p>
         <p xtrc="P">
                                    <i>Nuclear hot cell services,</i> as used in this subpart, means services related to the examination of, or performance of various operations on, nuclear fuel rods, control assemblies, or other components that are emitting large quantities of ionizing radiation, after discharge from nuclear reactors, which are performed in specialized facilities located away from commercial nuclear power plants, generally referred to in the industry as “hot cells.”
</p>
         <p xtrc="P">
                                    <i>Nuclear waste,</i> as used in this subpart, means any radioactive waste material subject to regulation by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission or the Department of Energy, or in the case of foreign offers, by comparable foreign organizations.
</p>
         <p xtrc="P">
                                    <i>United States company,</i> as used in this subpart, means a company which offers to perform nuclear hot cell services at a facility subject to the laws and regulations of the United States, its agencies, and its political subdivisions.
</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
