<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_915_404_4_71_3_T48_50320153117">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">915.404-4</ph>-71-3 Factors for determining fees.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p outputclass="List1">(a) The profit policy stated in 915.404-4-71-1(a) reflects, in a broad sense, recognition that profit is compensation to contractors for the entrepreneurial function of organizing and managing resources (including capital resources), and the assumption of risk that all costs of performance (operating and capital) may not be reimbursable.
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(b) The best approach calls for a structure that allows judgmental evaluation and determination of fee dollars for prescribed factors which impact the need for, and the rewards associated with, fee or profit, as follows - 
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(1) Management risk relating to performance, including the - 
</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(i) Quality and diversity of principal work tasks required to do the job;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(ii) Labor intensity of the job;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(iii) Special control problems; and
</p>
         <p outputclass="List3">(iv) Advance planning, forecasting and other such requirements;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(2) The presence or absence of financial risk, including the type and terms of the contract;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(3) The relative difficulty of work, including consideration of technical and administrative knowledge, skill, experience and clarity of technical specifications;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(4) Degree and amount of contract work required to be performed by and with the contractor's own resources, including the extent to which the contractor contributes plant, equipment, computers, or working capital (labor, etc.);
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(5) Duration of project;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(6) Size of operation;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(7) Benefits which may accrue to the contractor from gaining experience and know-how, from establishing or enhancing a reputation, or from being enabled to hold or expand a staff whose loyalties are primarily to the contractor; and
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(8) Other special considerations, including support of Government programs such as those relating to small, small disadvantaged, and women-owned small business in subcontracting, energy conservation, etc.
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(c) The total fee objective and amount for a particular negotiation is established by judgmental considerations of the factors in paragraph (b) of this section, assigning fee values as deemed appropriate for each factor and totaling the resulting amounts.
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(d) In recognition of the complexities of this process, and to assist in promoting a reasonable degree of consistency and uniformity in its application, fee schedules have been developed which set forth maximum fee amounts that contracting activities are allowed to negotiate for a particular transaction without obtaining prior approval of the Senior Procurement Executive. In addition, the fee negotiation objective established in accordance with 915.404-4-71-3(a), (b), and (c) shall not exceed the applicable fee schedule amounts without prior approval of the Senior Procurement Executive. To facilitate application to a contract, the fee amounts are related to the total cost base which is defined as total operating and capital costs.
</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
