<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_1652_222_70_T48_60215241111">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">1652.222-70</ph> Notice of significant events.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p xtrc="P">As prescribed in <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_1622_103_70_T48_6021212111"
                  href="Section_1622_103_70_T48_6021212111.dita#Section_1622_103_70_T48_6021212111">1622.103-70</xref>, the following clause shall be inserted in all FEHBP contracts.
</p>
                                    <p xtrc="HD1">Notice of Significant Events (JUL 2005)
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(a) The Carrier agrees to notify OPM of any Significant Event within ten (10) working days after the Carrier becomes aware of it. As used in this section, a Significant Event is any occurrence or anticipated occurrence that might reasonably be expected to have a material effect upon the Carrier's ability to meet its obligations under this contract, including, but not limited to, any of the following: 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(1) Disposal of major assets; 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(2) Loss of 15% or more of the Carrier's overall membership; 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(3) Termination or modification of any contract or subcontract if such termination or modification might have a material effect on the Carrier's obligations under this contract; 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(4) Addition or termination of provider agreements;
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(5) Any changes in underwriters, reinsurers, or participating plans; 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(6) The imposition of, or notice of the intent to impose, a receivership, conservatorship, or special regulatory monitoring; 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(7) The withdrawal of, or notice of intent to withdraw, State licensing, HHS qualification, or any other status under Federal or State law; 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(8) Default on a loan or other financial obligation; 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(9) Any actual or potential labor dispute that delays or threatens to delay timely performance or substantially impairs the functioning of the Carrier's facilities or facilities used by the Carrier in the performance of the contract; 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(10) Any change in its charter, constitution, or by-laws which affects any provision of this contract or the Carrier's participation in the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program; or 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(11) Any significant changes in policies and procedures or interpretations of the contract or brochure which would affect the benefits available under the contract or the costs charged to the contract. 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(12) Any fraud, embezzlement or misappropriation of FEHB funds; or
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(13) Any written exceptions, reservations or qualifications expressed by the independent accounting firm (which ascribes to the standards of the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants) contracted with by the Carrier to provide an opinion on its annual financial statements.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(b) Upon learning of a Significant Event OPM may institute action, in proportion to the seriousness of the event, to protect the interest of Members, including, but not limited to - 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(1) Directing the Carrier to take corrective action;
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(2) Suspending new enrollments under this contract;
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(3) Advising Enrollees of the Significant Event and providing them an opportunity to transfer to another plan;
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(4) Withholding payment of subscription income or restricting access to the Carrier's Letter of Credit account.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(5) Terminating the enrollment of those enrollees who, in the judgment of OPM, would be adversely affected by the Significant Event; or
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(6) Terminating this contract pursuant to section 1.15, renewal and withdrawal of approval. 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(c) Prior to taking action as described in paragraph (b) of this clause, the OPM will notify the Carrier and offer an opportunity to respond. 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(d) The carrier will insert this clause in any subcontract or subcontract modification if the amount of the subcontract or modification charged to the FEHB Program (or in the case of a community-rated carrier, applicable to the FEHB Program) equals or exceeds $550,000 and is at least 25 percent of the total subcontract cost. The amount of the dollar charge to the FEHB Program shall be adjusted by the same amount and at the same time as any change to the threshold for application of the Truth in Negotiations Act pursuant to 41 U.S.C. 254b(a)(7).</p>
                                 <p xtrc="HD3">(End of clause)
</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
