<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_2052_235_71_T48_60638251133">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">2052.235-71</ph> Safety, health, and fire protection.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p xtrc="P">As prescribed in <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_2035_70_T48_6063622011"
                  href="Section_2035_70_T48_6063622011.dita#Section_2035_70_T48_6063622011">2035.70</xref>(a)(2), the contracting officer shall insert the following clause in applicable solicitations and contracts for research and development by private contractors and universities and for other technical services as appropriate:
</p>
                                    <p xtrc="HD1">Safety, Health, and Fire Protection (JAN 1993)
</p>
                                    <p xtrc="P">The contractor shall take all reasonable precautions in the performance of the work under this contract to protect the health and safety of its employees and of members of the public, including NRC employees and contractor personnel, and to minimize danger from all hazards to life and property. The contractor shall comply with all applicable health, safety, and fire protection regulations and requirements (including reporting requirements) of the Commission and the Department of Labor. If the contractor fails to comply with these regulations or requirements, the contracting officer may, without prejudice to any other legal or contractual rights of the Commission, issue an order stopping all or any part of the work. Thereafter, a start work order for resumption of work may be issued at the discretion of the contracting officer. The contractor may not make a claim for an extension of time or for compensation or damages by reason of, or in connection with, this type of work stoppage.</p>
                                 <p xtrc="HD3">(End of clause)


</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
