<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   " ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	<concept id="d1e17535" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3" domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   " class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		<title class="- topic/title ">225.502 APPLICATION.</title>
		<conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
			<p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(a)  Whenever the acquisition is in support of operations in Afghanistan, treat the offers of end products from South Caucasus or Central and South Asian states listed in 225.401-70 the same as qualifying country offers.</p>
			<p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(b)  Use the following procedures instead of the procedures in FAR 25.502(b) for acquisitions subject to the World Trade Organization Government Procurement Agreement:</p>
			<p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(i)  Consider only offers of U.S.-made, qualifying country, or designated country end products, except as permitted by 225.403 or 225.7703-1.</p>
			<p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(ii)  If price is the determining factor, award on the low offer.</p>
			<p outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(c)  Use the following procedures instead of those in FAR 25.502(c) for acquisitions subject to the Buy American statute or the Balance of Payments Program:</p>
			<p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(i)(A)  If the acquisition is subject only to the Buy American statute or the Balance of Payments Program, then only qualifying country end products are exempt from application of the Buy American or Balance of Payments Program evaluation factor.</p>
			<p outputclass="List4" class="- topic/p ">(B)  If the acquisition is also subject to a Free Trade Agreement, then eligible products of the applicable Free Trade Agreement country are also exempt from application of the Buy American or Balance of Payments Program evaluation factor.</p>
			<p outputclass="List3" class="- topic/p ">(ii)  If price is the determining factor, use the following procedures:</p>
			<p outputclass="List4" class="- topic/p ">(A)  If the low offer is a domestic offer, award on that offer.</p>
		</conbody>
	</concept>
</dita>