<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_970_5222_2_T48_503264131119">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">970.5222-2</ph> Overtime management.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p xtrc="P">As prescribed in 970.2201-2-2, insert the following clause: 
</p>
                                    <p xtrc="HD1">Overtime Management (DEC 2000) 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(a) The Contractor shall maintain adequate internal controls to ensure that employee overtime is authorized only if cost effective and necessary to ensure performance of work under this contract. 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(b) The Contractor shall notify the Contracting Officer when in any given year it is likely that overtime usage as a percentage of payroll may exceed 4%. 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(c) The Contracting Officer may require the submission, for approval, of a formal annual overtime control plan whenever Contractor overtime usage as a percentage of payroll has exceeded, or is likely to exceed, 4%, or if the Contracting Officer otherwise deems overtime expenditures excessive. The plan shall include, at a minimum -  
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(1) An overtime premium fund (maximum dollar amount); 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(2) Specific controls for casual overtime for non-exempt employees; 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(3) Specific parameters for allowability of exempt overtime; 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(4) An evaluation of alternatives to the use of overtime; and 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(5) Submission of a semi-annual report that includes for exempt and non-exempt employees -  
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List3">(i) Total cost of overtime; 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List3">(ii) Total cost of straight time; 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List3">(iii) Overtime cost as a percentage of straight-time cost; 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List3">(iv) Total overtime hours; 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List3">(v) Total straight-time hours; and 
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List3">(vi) Overtime hours as a percentage of straight-time hours.</p>
                                 <p xtrc="HD3">(End of clause)
</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
