<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_731_205_43_T48_501524212">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">731.205-43</ph> Trade, business, technical and professional activity costs - USAID conference approval requirements.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p outputclass="List1">(a) The contractor must obtain prior written approval from the contracting officer, or the contracting officer's representative (COR), if delegated in the Contracting Officer's Representative Designation Letter, for costs related to conferences funded in whole or in part with USAID funds when:
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(1) Twenty (20) or more USAID employees are expected to attend.
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(2) The net conference expense funded by USAID will exceed $100,000 (excluding salary of employees), regardless of the number of USAID participants.
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(b) The contracting officer or the contracting officer's representative will follow the internal Agency procedures for review and approval of conference costs, as specified in Automated Directive System (ADS) chapter 580, prior to providing such approval to the contractor.
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(c) Costs associated with a conference that meets the criteria above, incurred without USAID prior written approval, are unallowable.
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(d) Contracting officers must insert the clause at <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_752_231_72_T48_5018362128"
                  href="Section_752_231_72_T48_5018362128.dita#Section_752_231_72_T48_5018362128">752.231-72</xref> in all USAID-funded solicitations and contracts anticipated to include a requirement for a USAID-funded conference. See (48 CFR) AIDAR <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_752_231_72_T48_5018362128"
                  href="Section_752_231_72_T48_5018362128.dita#Section_752_231_72_T48_5018362128">752.231-72</xref> for the definition of a conference and specific requirements and procedures.
</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
