<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_736_602_3_T48_501628212">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">736.602-3</ph> Evaluation board functions.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p xtrc="P">Agency architect-engineer evaluation boards shall perform the following functions:
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(a) Prepare a selection memorandum recommending no less than three firms which are considered most highly qualified to perform the required services for submission to the head of the contracting activity for his/her approval. This selection memorandum shall include the information specified in <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_736_602_3_T48_501628212"
                  href="Section_736_602_3_T48_501628212.dita#Section_736_602_3_T48_501628212">736.602-3</xref>(c).</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(b) In evaluating architect-engineer firms, the architect-engineer evaluation board shall apply the following criteria, other criteria established by Agency regulations, and any criteria set forth in the public notice on a particular contract:
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(1) Specialized experience of the firm (including each member of joint venture or association) with the type of service required;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(2) Capacity of the firm to perform the work (including any specialized services) within the time limitations;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(3) Past record of performance on contracts with USAID or other Government agencies and private industry with respect to such factors as control of costs, quality of work, and ability to meet schedules, to the extent such information is available;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(4) Ability to assign an adequate number of qualified key personnel from the organization, including a competent supervising representative having considerable experience in responsible positions on work of a similar nature;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(5) The portions of the work the architect-engineer is able to perform with its own forces when required;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(6) Ability of the architect-engineer to furnish or to obtain required materials and equipment;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(7) If the geographical or topographical aspects of the project are deemed vital, familiarity with the locality where the project is situated;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(8) Financial capacity;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(9) Responsibility of the architect-engineer under standards provided in (48 CFR) FAR subpart 9.1. No contract may be awarded to a contractor that does not meet these standards;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(10) Volume of work previously awarded to the firm by the Agency, with the object of effecting an equitable distribution of architect-engineer contracts among qualified firms. Each architect-engineer evaluation board shall give favorable consideration, to the fullest extent practicable to the most highly qualified firms that have not had prior experience on Government projects (including small business firms and firms owned by the socially and/or economically deprived).
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(c) The evaluation board shall prepare a selection memorandum for the approval of the head of the contracting activity. The selection memorandum will be signed by the board chairman and cleared by each board member. The selection memorandum shall include the following information:
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(1) A listing by name of all firms reviewed by the board;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(2) A listing of the evaluation criteria applied;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(3) An analysis of the selection showing the rationale for the board's recommendation;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(4) The board's recommendation of the three most highly qualified firms, in order of preference;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(5) An independent Government cost estimate. The evaluation board shall require the project engineer to develop an independent Government estimate of the cost of the required architect-engineer services. Consideration shall be given to the estimated value of the services to be rendered, the scope, complexity, and the nature of the project and the estimated costs expected to be generated by the work. The independent Government estimate shall be revised as required during negotiations to correct noted deficiencies and reflect changes in or clarification of, the scope of the work to be performed by the architect-engineer. A cost estimate based on the application of percentage factors to cost estimates of the various segments of the work involved, e.g., construction project, may be developed for comparison purposes, but such a cost estimate shall not be used as a substitute for the independent Government estimate.
</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
