<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_704_404_T48_50115111">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">704.404</ph> Contract clauses.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p outputclass="List1">(a) When the contract includes a requirement for the contractor to access classified (“Confidential”, “Secret”, or “Top Secret”), or administratively controlled (“Sensitive But Unclassified”) information, the contracting officer must insert (48 CFR) FAR clause 52.204-2, Security Requirements and (48 CFR) AIDAR clause <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_752_204_2_T48_501836213"
                  href="Section_752_204_2_T48_501836213.dita#Section_752_204_2_T48_501836213">752.204-2</xref>, Security Requirements, in the solicitation and award.
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(b) If the contract requires the contractor (or contractor employees) to have routine physical access to USAID-controlled facilities in the U.S. (<i>i.e.,</i> will need an ID for regular entry to USAID space), or have logical access to USAID's information systems (<i>i.e.,</i> access to AIDNet, Phoenix, the Global Acquisition and Assistance System (GLAAS,) etc.,) and the solicitation and contract contains (48 CFR) FAR 52.204-9(a), the contracting officer must also insert (48 CFR) AIDAR <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_752_204_72_T48_501836216"
                  href="Section_752_204_72_T48_501836216.dita#Section_752_204_72_T48_501836216">752.204-72</xref>, Access to USAID Facilities and USAID's Information Systems. Only U.S citizen employees or consultants of a U.S.-based company may request routine physical access to USAID-controlled facilities or logical access to USAID's information systems.
</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
