<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_752_222_70_T48_5018362114">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">752.222-70</ph> USAID disability policy.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p xtrc="P">As prescribed in <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref "
                  base="Section_722_810_T48_501417212"
                  href="Section_722_810_T48_501417212.dita#Section_722_810_T48_501417212">722.810</xref>, the contracting officer must insert the following clause in Section H of all solicitations and resulting awards.
</p>
                                    <p xtrc="HD1">USAID Disability Policy (DEC 2004)
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(a) The objectives of the USAID Disability Policy are:
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(1) To enhance the attainment of United States foreign assistance program goals by promoting the participation and equalization of opportunities of individuals with disabilities in USAID policy, country and sector strategies, activity designs and implementation;
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(2) To increase awareness of issues of people with disabilities both within USAID programs and in host countries;
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(3) To engage other U.S. Government agencies, host country counterparts, governments, implementing organizations and other donors in fostering a climate of nondiscrimination against people with disabilities; and
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List2">(4) To support international advocacy for people with disabilities. The full text of USAID's policy can be found at the following Web site: <i>http://pdf.usaid.gov/pdf_docs/PDABQ631.pdf</i>.
</p>
                                    <p outputclass="List1">(b) USAID therefore requires that the contractor not discriminate against people with disabilities in the implementation of USAID programs and that it make every effort to comply with the objectives of the USAID Disability Policy in performing this contract. To that end and within the scope of the contract, the contractor's actions must demonstrate a comprehensive and consistent approach for including men, women, and children with disabilities.</p>
                                 </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
