<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept outputclass="Section" id="Section_750_7107_T48_5017352112">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber">750.7107</ph> Limitations upon exercise of authority.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p outputclass="List1">(a) The Executive Order is not authority for:
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(1) The use of the cost-plus-a-percentage-of-cost system of contracting;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(2) The making of any contract in violation of existing law relating to limitation on profit or fees;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(3) The waiver of any bid, payment performance or other bond required by law.
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(b) No amendments, or modifications shall be entered into under the authority of the Executive Order:
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(1) Unless, with respect to cases falling within Section 4 of the Executive Order, a finding is made that the action is necessary to protect the foreign policy interests of the United States;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(2) Unless other legal authority in the Agency is deemed to be lacking or inadequate;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(3) Except within the limits of the amounts appropriated and the statutory contract authorization.
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(c) No contract shall be amended or modified unless the request therefor has been filed before all obligations (including final payment) under the contract have been discharged.
</p>
         <p outputclass="List1">(d) No informal commitment shall be formalized unless:
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(1) A request for payment has been filed within six months after arranging to furnish or furnishing property or services in reliance upon the commitment;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(2) USAID has received the services satisfactorily performed, or has accepted property furnished in reliance on the commitment;
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(3) The USAID employees alleged to have made the informal commitment have accepted responsibility for making the informal commitment in question; and
</p>
         <p outputclass="List2">(4) USAID has taken appropriate action to prevent recurrence.
</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
